modernsurvivalblog.com 2019-08-23

# Privacy Policy

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://modernsurvivalblog.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

(referenced in the following sections)

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

This site uses Akismet to reduce comment spam. The information Akismet collects depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

### Contact forms

We use a contact form on this site to enable contact submission to our email address. We do not use the information for marketing purposes.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. This is for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

### Analytics

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on ModernSurvivalBlog.com. Google’s use of cookies enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to ModernSurvivalBlog.com and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL, <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

## Who we share your data with

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners may include, but are not limited to, Google and Amazon.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks may use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on ModernSurvivalBlog.com sent directly to your browsers. They may automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

ModernSurvivalBlog.com has no access to, or control over, these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. ModernSurvivalBlog.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata may be retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Contact information

You may contact us by using our ‘Contact Us’ form located in the footer below.

### How we protect your data

We utilize state of the art safeguards and firewall protection services to protect ModernSurvivalBlog.com and its users. We have also implemented “https” encryption protocol.

Terms of Use  
Disclaimer
